<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ggplot2 on My take on data</title>
    <link>/tags/ggplot2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ggplot2 on My take on data</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/ggplot2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does everyone I work with have the same name? A guide on how to not pick a unique baby name in America.</title>
      <link>/2019/10/baby-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/baby-names/</guid>
      <description>I’ve taken a particular interest in names since I’m thinking of a name for my to-be-born son. I did a little digging through the Social Security Administration names database, which lists all names given to baby boys and girls in America1. I began this exercise to just get a quality list of ideas, but my curiosity got the better of me.
Name Trends Since 1950 What was the most popular boy name since 1950?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>byu football</title>
      <link>/2018/09/byu-football/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/byu-football/</guid>
      <description>Goal of this post. Answer some interesting questions about BYU football. Dive into different modeling approaches. I don’t explain my thinking below, but some of the charts might be cool.
Some questions of interest
 How is Kilani Sitake doing in his second season compared to past BYU coaches? More challenging: how’s he doing relative to all second-season coaches?  df_in &amp;lt;- read.csv(file.path(fp_data, &amp;#39;byu_seasons.csv&amp;#39;)) %&amp;gt;% distinct() Some basic questions: * How many years do we have data on?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The DataViz battle: Plotly vs ggplot2</title>
      <link>/2017/02/the-dataviz-battle-plotly-vs-ggplot2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/02/the-dataviz-battle-plotly-vs-ggplot2/</guid>
      <description>R users fall in love with ggplot2, the growing standard for data visualization in R. The ability to quickly vizualize trends, and customize just about anything you’d want, make it a powerful tool. Yet this week, I made a discovery that may reduce how much I used ggplot2. Enter plot_ly().
For this post, I assume that you have a working knowledge of the dplyr (or magrittr) and ggplot2 packages.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>